<section>
<title>Extracting Documentation with ROBODoc</title>

    <para>Now that you have prepared your source code for use with
    ROBODoc you are ready to extract the documentation.  There are
    several choices to be made.</para>

<section>
<title>Single document or many smaller documents</title>

    <para>First of all, ROBODoc can be used in three modes.</para>

    <itemizedlist> 

    <listitem><para>multidoc -- in this mode ROBODoc scans
    all the source files in your source directory and creates a
    separate document file for each of these in a document directory.
    The document directory is created automatically. Its structure is
    a mirror of the structure of your source directory.</para></listitem> 

    <listitem><para>singledoc -- in this mode ROBODoc scans all the source
    files in your source directory and creates a single documentation
    file that contains all the documentation extracted from your
    source files.  </para></listitem>

    <listitem><para>singlefile -- in this mode ROBODoc scans a single source
    file and creates a single documentation file.</para></listitem>

    </itemizedlist>
</section>

<section>
<title>multidoc</title>

    <para>The multidoc mode is useful to create browsable documents.
    For instance many small HTML files that can be viewed with a
    web-browser.  This mode requires the following arguments:</para>

    <para>
    <command>robodoc
    --src <replaceable>source directory</replaceable>
    --doc <replaceable>document directory</replaceable>
    --multidoc
    other options
    </command>
</para>

    <para>An additional option that is useful with this mode is
    <option>--index</option>, this creates a series of index files,
    one for each header type.</para>

</section>


<section>
<title>singledoc</title>

    <para> The singledoc mode is useful to create bulk documentation
    that can be incorporated in other documents, or that can be
    delivered to a client as a single document.  For instance a file
    created in RTF format can be included into a larger design
    document written in Word format.  This mode requires the following
    arguments:</para>

<para>
    <command>robodoc
        --src <replaceable>source directory</replaceable>
        --doc <replaceable>document file without extension</replaceable>
        --singledoc
        <replaceable>other options</replaceable>
    </command>
</para>

    <para>An additional option that is useful with this mode is
    <option>--sections</option>, this causes the headers to follow a
    section layout based on the module element hierarchy defined in the
    header name.</para>

</section>


<section>
<title>singlefile</title>

    <para>The singlefile mode is not very useful.  It is mainly used
    for debugging purposes.  This mode requires the following
    arguments:</para>

<para>
    <command>robodoc
    --src <replaceable>source file</replaceable>
    --doc <replaceable>document file</replaceable>
    --singlefile
    other options
</command>
</para>

</section>

<section>
<title>Output formats</title>

    <para>Your next choice is the output format. ROBODoc can create
    documentation in several formats:</para>

    <itemizedlist> 
    <listitem><para>HTML, option <option>--html</option></para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>RTF, option <option>--rtf</option></para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>LaTeX, option <option>--latex</option></para></listitem> 
    <listitem><para>XML DocBook, option <option>--dbxml</option></para></listitem> 
    </itemizedlist>

    <para>What format to use depends on your wishes. If you want a
    single printable document, use LaTeX or XML DocBook.  If you want
    a document that can be included into a larger (Word) document use
    RTF.  If you want something that is browsable use HTML, or use XML
    DocBook and then convert it to HTML.</para>

</section>
</section>

